Stop trying
to put on a tough front around your friends,
Natsuki Subaru!
Your head is just a big, jumbled mess,
and you don't know what to do, right?
You keep getting into situations where
you have to reach out and help,
but both your arms and your head
are too weak to reach far enough,
so you end up just wasting time
frantically flailing around, right?
Do you hear me?
If you hear me, say something!
What the hell was that for?!
You finally lost your temper,
but you forgot to pay
attention to your footing.
That just sums you up perfectly, doesn't it?
Pathetic.
Oh, is that right?!
That's really all the strength you have.
Putting on a tough act for
a girl you love is fine.
And you can play tough for
a girl who likes you, too.
No one would object to that.
But that's as far as it goes!
You know you're not good enough, don't you?
You know you can't reach, don't you?
You want to look good for the
girl you like, don't you?!
You want to be someone the girl who
likes you can be proud of, don't you?!
Then why don't you just
accept someone's help?!
Someone like...
a friend!
I did rely on someone else.
I asked for help.
But it didn't work.
Maybe...
But I don't recall ever
hearing you ask for my help.
N-No, I mean...
My head is just full of knots.
It's full of stuff you wouldn't
believe even if I told you.
I don't even know how to start...
Just start talking.
I'll listen until you finish.
But if I do that—
Didn't I just tell you not
to put on that tough act?!
If you have time to overcomplicate
everything in your head,
then just spit it all out!
Easy for you to say, but I—
Spit out all of those knots!
And when you're done,
just tell me to believe you!
Because we're friends!
You might not believe me, but...
Roswaal!
Let's make a bet,
with my wish and yours on the line!
I certainly did not expect to
see you again in this life.
This will be our last showdown.
I'm going to save the Sanctuary
and the mansion in this loop,
whatever it takes.
And I'll bust up every
damn one of your plans!
You think you can start
over, from this dead end,
and leave behind the one
and only power you have?
Being able to start over and being able
to save them are two different things.
Both you and I were too arrogant.
This power I have isn't even that useful.
If you say this is the last time,
what is it you want from me?
My demand is simple.
If I save both the Sanctuary
and the mansion,
you will throw that book
away and come with me.
I'm going to make Emilia the new ruler,
And to do that , I will need your help.
Don't be ridiculous.
That suggestion is absolutely warped.
Do you think you would
forgive what I—
If this was about forgiving you,
there's no way in hell I'd ever do that.
But that's for my own heart to worry about.
Nothing deadly has happened yet.
So if I can solve this... you know...
How can an idea be so convenient?
Hey, I love convenient ideas!
Emilia's gonna do her best
to become the next ruler,
I'll be by her side to congratulate her.
And you'll be one of the
people surrounding her.
Just so you know, you're mandatory.
You expect to fulfill your desire
without letting go of anything?
Not only that, but you say
my involvement is necessary
and insist on including me in
the foundation for the future?
Do you understand Subaru-kun?
Of what?
Amount of sheer greed your answer has.
Your enemy has become the
strongest card in play.
That's still not enough for you?
No matter how hard you fight it,
you cannot break through this.
With Emilia-sama unable to stand,
the barrier will remain.
The Sanctuary will be covered in snow,
and the mansion will sink
into a bloody tragedy.
Yeah. Should make the sight
of you crying all the better.
I see. You are right.
It isn't a bad idea to lay some
groundwork for the next me.
So can I take that to mean
you agree to the bet?
Well, If that's settled,
then let's get it started.
Subaru-kun...
The snow in the Sanctuary and the attack
on the mansion begin in three days.
Do try your hardest to fight it...
and fail miserably.
Say what you want.
Roswaal, put the clown makeup back on,
You're throwing me off my stride.
As two clowns at the mercy of fate,
let's fight this out fair and square.
How is the scheming
with you're with your friend going?
What about you?
Do you accept what Roswaal's doing?
There's only one thing
I value above all else.
There's no way that will ever change. Never.
So stop hoping that
I will change my mind.
Never say never.
Watch your mouth.
Are you placing your hopes in Emilia-sama?
Yes, I am, and I believe in her.
Emilia-sama hasn't figured out
why she's been struggling.
Until she does, the same thing
will just keep happening.
We've already strayed from
what's written in the book.
Roswaal is free now!
She gave me a honest advice...
If wonder If she likes me, too?
You're still talking like that?
If she heard that, she'd be furious.
Since Ram-san is working with the margrave,
doesn't that make you enemies?
Ram is an enemy?
Well, now I can see how
deeply you trust Ram-san.
And? What happened with
the margrave himself?
Everything's set.
The bet is officially on.
That is good to hear.
Well, the margrave didn't seem to
have ever lost at anything before,
so I knew he would agree.
And next is...
Garfiel, yeah.
But first, can I just check into one thing?
Very well. I'll do my part
of the plan as discussed.
And, as for Emilia-sama...
That's one thing where
I can't rely on you.
Or should I say I can't
rely on myself either.
I haven't even scratched the
surface of what's hurting her.
I guess I was just scared, after all.
Indeed.
Don't try to play innocent.
Hey, man!
So are you prepared to scratch the
surface of what's hurting her?
Well, I'm prepared to ask her if I can.
Unlike with Garfiel,
I don't have to worry about dying.
I'm not sure if I should
laugh at that or not.
Then again, you took a bet
that was stacked against you, too.
I suppose so.
But taking on a bet without even
considering my odds of winning?
That's a first for me.
I thought I'd find you here, Ryuzu-san.
You talk like someone who already
knows me remarkably well.
I'd say you're right. I know
just about everything.
I even know what your goal is here.
Then I suppose the one Young Ros
was waiting for was you.
Yeah, sorry. That whole
thing's been called off.
Hah?
Anyway, I'm in the middle of a
huge face-off with Roswaal now.
I want it to end in a result
that's good for everyone,
which is why I want your help.
Why not use your jurisdiction as an
apostle to demand my assistance?
I don't want to rely on
that kind of jurisdiction.
I came here to talk to you.
Young men are so quick
to put on a tough front.
And? What is it you are arguing over?
In simple terms, I guess I'd say
a way to liberate the Sanctuary.
I know you're opposed to
liberating it, though.
I am opposed to liberating the Sanctuary?
Huh? Wait, you're not opposed to it?
Haeh?! Are you for real?
Then why did you...
Still, I cannot say that your
suspicions are entirely wild.
What is your opinion of Young Gar?
I think... there's no
avoiding a clash with him.
I see.
But...
whether we can get along or not
after all this is over, is yet to be seen.
And to help me make that decision,
I want to know more about him.
You are quite skilled at deceiving
the elderly, Young Su.
You asked the witch about me, did you not?
About the copies of Ryuzu Meyer,
and perhaps about the
purpose of creating them.
I heard about the immortality experiment
and that you Ryuzus were
the successful cases for it.
To this day, I protect and supervise
the crystal that creates the copies.
The four of us alternate in
bearing the role of supervisor.
I did hear about the "first four."
So the other three besides you...
My name is Natsuki Subaru.
What's your name, Ryuzu-san?
My name is Ryuzu Arma.
I am one of the first four copies.
Arma?
I am Ryuzu Bilma.
The first Ryuzu-san I met
called herself "Bilma."
I never meant to hide
anything from Ryuzu-san...
But why go through so much hassle?
Our bodies are not made of flesh and blood.
They are made of artificial
od clothed in mana.
All activity we engage in consumes the mana,
and continuous activity for
a full day is impossible.
Oh, so you're like the spirits.
That's why you've been alternating
between each other.
But... are you okay with that?
You are so kind, Young Su.
However, one of the first four,
Ryuzu Shima, is an exception.
Ryuzu Shima?
I will tell no one what you told me.
I swear it on the name of Ryuzu Shima.
About ten years ago, she caused a problem.
She was then removed from
the role of supervisor,
and now lives in the forest
with the other copies.
For that reason, three of us
fulfill the supervisor role now.
What problem did she cause?
She violated the contract with
the witch who created us
by entering the graveyard...
to bring back Young Gar
when he broke the rules to attempt
the trial and did not return.
I have not seen Shima since
she was stripped of her duty,
but it would be no surprise
if Young Gar has been meeting with Shima,
with whom he shares memories that we do not.
Memories that you three don't have?
I refer to the past that Young Gar
saw in the graveyard trial.
Are you aware of Young Gar's family situation?
Yeah, I know Frederica is his
sister from a different father,
and since she has less non-human blood,
she left the Sanctuary ten years ago.
Why did you leave the Sanctuary?
I suppose I wanted to create
an opportunity for the
people of the Sanctuary
to leave it once the barrier was broken.
I wanted to make a place for them.
At least, that's what she said.
Wait, did the past that Garfiel
saw involve the time she left?
No, what he saw was most likely
the moment when Young Gar
and Fred were left behind
by their mother when she left the Sanctuary.
That foolish, pitiful Garfiel
fears the outside world.
So the reason he's against
liberating the Sanctuary
is out of bitterness toward his mother for
abandoning him and choosing the outside?
The boy refers to himself as Garfiel Tinzel.
That is his mother's family name.
I believe he goes by that name
so that he won't forget her.
Whether it was out of anger or sadness
is most likely known only to him and Shima.
Emilia-tan?
Huh?
Subaru?
What're you doing down there, Emilia-tan?
You'll get your butt dirty.
Um... I'm a restless sleeper.
Sorry... I lied.
The truth is, I couldn't get to sleep.
But don't worry. I'll be sure to
get plenty of sleep by tonight.
It's almost noon, though.
You're talking about
sleeping until nightfall?
That's very slothful of you, Emilia-tan.
The way you said that...
just gives me a really weird feeling.
Ugh, Subaru, you meanie.
Thank you.
Emilia, do you feel up to telling
me what you saw during the trial?
I won't claim that talking about
it will make you feel better.
But if you tell me, we can
carry that burden together.
I don't know if I can be of any help...
but would you give me the right to
fight the same enemies you fight?
Subaru...
Subaru, you have so much faith in me...
The...
The past I saw...
was a memory from before
I went to sleep, I think.
I never told you that I was frozen
in ice for a long time, did I?
Frozen in... ice?
I was frozen in the forest for a long time.
Until Puck found me and got me out,
I had been sleeping within the
ice for a long, long time.
How long?
Since I was... six or
seven years old, maybe?
We all lived in the forest together
before it froze, I think.
You think?
I don't remember much from
before that happened.
What about your family?
My family wasn't in the forest.
But there was someone who
was like a mother to me...
Huh?
Eh, why...
Mo.. ther?
Calm down. Take it slow.
What happened to all of them?
The same... as me.
They were frozen in ice.
I lived in the forest,
always waiting with Puck
for everyone to wake up.
But that day never came.
That's why... I left the forest
and joined in the royal selection.
Huh?
What does the forest have to
do with the royal selection?
Roswaal made me a promise...
If you succeed in taking the throne,
perhaps I can thaw the ice
that encases this forest.
Do you despise me?
All the other candidates are participating
with admirable goals and resolutions,
but my reason is so, soo selfish.
Is that the "selfish reason"
you were talking about?
There's nothing bad about wanting
to save the people you care about.
Even if you don't save many people,
It's still an admirable deed.
Yeah...
Thank you... soo much.
Emilia?
Do the memories that Emilia can't recall
hold some clue to getting through the trial?
Maybe Emilia can't remember,
but if I ask the guy who does...
I'm sorry, Emilia.
Ow!
You didn't have to go that far, did you?!
Oh, I wonder...
Your love seems like the needy type,
so I'm a little scared to
let you stay beside Lia.
Should I erase you?
Don't say that like it's no big deal!
Regardless, Emilia-tan's really sad
since her family-member-slash-pet ran off.
"Ran off" you say?
I've always been inside her.
It was good of you to call me, though.
I'm glad, Subaru.
Emilia!
Did you have another scary dream?
Puck?!
Thank goodness! Where have you been?
I was so worried!
Don't disappear like that again!
Puck?
Do I look a little smaller than usual?
I guess my limit came up
faster than I thought.
Of course, I was consciously
trying to breach our contract,
so I guess it makes sense that I'd lose
my greatest strengths as a spirit.
Breach... our contract?
Wh-What are you saying?
I've been by your side all this time.
I couldn't tell you only for
my own personal reasons,
and because of your own problems.
But from now on...
Huh?
Eh? No, eh... W-Wait, please!
Th-This is terrible, Puck!
The stone... The stone you reside in...
I'm sorry, Lia.
I wish I could explain everything,
but there's no time.
As much as it frustrates me,
I'm entrusting you to the one whose
love for you is second only to mine.
What... are you saying?
There's no... There's no such person...
Lia...
I'm terminating the contract
between you and me.
I really am sorry this
turned out so one-sided.
Once I'm gone, the seal on
your memories will be lifted.
Remembering them will
probably make you very sad.
You might want to cry more
than you do right now.
Emilia...
I love you so, so much.
No...
That should do.
Lia...
I love you more than anyone in the world.
Emilia-sama fell unconscious?
Yeah, the spirit user's spirit left her.
If it drives her so nuts
that she'd miss the trial,
then she’s of no use
Do not say that.
This is a matter of the heart,
so it makes me sad for her.
Incidentally, Young Gar, about Young Su...
The dude who's covered in miasma?
Indeed. I do know what I said before,
but he does not appear to have
any connection with the witch.
I wonder.
Get yourself to bed, you doddering old hag.
"A rudy that stays up all night will
regret having short legs," ya know.
Emilia, are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm sure... I will be.
I like to believe I'll
be fine by morning.
A-Anyway, just don't fret over it too much!
If there's anything I can do...
Well, I don't have much to offer,
but it's all yours.
Emilia?
Hold my hand.
Will you stay here until morning?
If you do...
I think I can...
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Please...
If this is what you want, that's easy.
Once it's morning... once
tomorrow comes, you'll be fine.
I believe in you.
Yeah.
Emilia!
I'm sorry, Emilia. I'm so sorry.
All the people who told you that kind lie,
that they wanted to protect you...
Please don't hate them.
Emilia, I love you so much.
Mother Fortuna, you liar.
Puck, you liar.
And Subaru... you liar.
Emilia-sama!
Did you find her?
No.
Emilia-sama!
Ram, what's all the noise for?
Garf...
Do you know where Emilia-sama went?
What?
Emilia-sama has disappeared.
We've all split up to search for her.
All right. I'll start lookin' around here.
Hey, Granny! You awake?
Someone might come by
lookin' for the princess.
You better go—
Granny?! Granny!
Somethin' doesn't feel right.
Granny! You in here?!
Not here, either.
No way. Did they...
Granny?!
I'm truly sorry to disappoint you...
But a friend asked me to help.
I realize I took the short end of the stick,
but I've set out to do it regardless.
Why You...
In truth, I had planned to talk
things over with you here.
Talk things over?
Yes, I wanted to talk to you with Ryuzu...
that is, with Shima-san in attendance.
But I really wasn't expecting
what happened with Emilia-sama.
That said, all kinds of conspiratorial
plans were already laid out.
So now that the host of the banquet is away,
how would you like me to play the host instead?
...wanted to protect you...
I'm so sorry.
Please don't hate them.
Emilia...
All the people who told you that kind lie...
I'm sorry.
I love you so much.
Ah, Thank god, Finally found you.
Subaru?
Well, let's have a talk,
Emilia-tan.